<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xiaotong Yao</title>
    <link>https://xtyao.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Xiaotong Yao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://xtyao.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My first blog in Chinese 中文第一篇</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/blog/chinese/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/blog/chinese/</guid>
      <description>博客文章一些会用中文写，请不要介意。太久不动笔，中文写作能力急需恢复。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing my first blog</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/blog/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/blog/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is awesome. Its so easy it makes you want to write.
I&amp;rsquo;m gonna start writing here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distinct Classes of Complex Structural Variation Uncovered across Thousands of Cancer Genome Graphs.</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/jabba/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/jabba/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Cancer genomes often harbor hundreds of somatic DNA rearrangement junctions, many of which cannot be easily classified into simple (e.g., deletion) or complex (e.g., chromothripsis) structural variant classes. Applying a novel genome graph computational paradigm to analyze the topology of junction copy number (JCN) across 2,778 tumor whole-genome sequences, we uncovered three novel complex rearrangement phenomena: pyrgo, rigma, and tyfonas. Pyrgo are “towers” of low-JCN duplications associated with early-replicating regions, superenhancers, and breast or ovarian cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural variant evolution after telomere crisis</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/telcrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/telcrisis/</guid>
      <description>Full text
Abstract Telomere crisis contributes to cancer genome evolution, yet only a subset of cancers display breakage-fusion-bridge (BFB) cycles and chromothripsis, hallmarks of previous experimental telomere crisis studies. We examine the spectrum of SVs instigated by natural telomere crisis. Spontaneous post-crisis clones from prior studies had both complex and simple SVs without BFB cycles or chromothripsis. In contrast, BFB cycles and chromothripsis occurred in clones that escaped from telomere crisis after CRISPR-controlled telomerase activation in MRC5 fibroblasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whole-genome characterization of lung adenocarcinomas lacking alterations in RTK/RAS/RAF pathway</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/gdan_luad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/gdan_luad/</guid>
      <description>Abstract Lung adenocarcinomas (LUAD) are typically characterized by genetic activation of the receptor tyrosine kinase (RTK)/RAS/RAF/MAP kinase (MAPK) pathway. A minority of LUAD cases (20-25%) lack apparent genetic alterations in this pathway, and thus are ineligible for most targeted therapies. These candidate “oncogene negative” LUADs may harbor novel classes of oncogenic drivers or represent a biologically distinct class of tumors. To characterize the genomic landscape of oncogene-negative LUADs, we nominated 98 cases that were found to lack an activating RTK/RAS/RAF/MAPK pathway alteration in a TCGA study utilizing whole exome sequencing, microarray, and transcriptome data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The evolutionary history of 2,658 cancers</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/pcawg_heterogeneity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/pcawg_heterogeneity/</guid>
      <description>Full text
Abstract Cancer develops through a process of somatic evolution1,2. Sequencing data from a single biopsy represent a snapshot of this process that can reveal the timing of specific genomic aberrations and the changing influence of mutational processes3. Here, by whole-genome sequencing analysis of 2,658 cancers as part of the Pan-Cancer Analysis of Whole Genomes (PCAWG) Consortium of the International Cancer Genome Consortium (ICGC) and The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA)4, we reconstruct the life history and evolution of mutational processes and driver mutation sequences of 38 types of cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyses of non-coding somatic drivers in 2,658 cancer whole genomes</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/pcawg_noncoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/pcawg_noncoding/</guid>
      <description>Full text
Abstract The discovery of drivers of cancer has traditionally focused on protein-coding genes1,2,3,4. Here we present analyses of driver point mutations and structural variants in non-coding regions across 2,658 genomes from the Pan-Cancer Analysis of Whole Genomes (PCAWG) Consortium5 of the International Cancer Genome Consortium (ICGC) and The Cancer Genome Atlas (TCGA). For point mutations, we developed a statistically rigorous strategy for combining significance levels from multiple methods of driver discovery that overcomes the limitations of individual methods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SvABA -- genome-wide detection of structural variants and indels by local assembly</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/svaba/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/svaba/</guid>
      <description>Full text
Abstract Structural variants (SVs), including small insertion and deletion variants (indels), are challenging to detect through standard alignment-based variant calling methods. Sequence assembly offers a powerful approach to identifying SVs, but is difficult to apply at scale genome-wide for SV detection due to its computational complexity and the difficulty of extracting SVs from assembly contigs. We describe SvABA, an efficient and accurate method for detecting SVs from short-read sequencing data using genome-wide local assembly with low memory and computing requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iSUMO - integrative prediction of functionally relevant SUMOylation events</title>
      <link>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/isumo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://xtyao.github.io/publications/isumo/</guid>
      <description>Full text
Abstract Post-translational modifications by the Small Ubiquitin-like Modifier (SUMO) are essential for diverse cellular functions. Large-scale experiment and sequence-based predictions have identified thousands of SUMOylated proteins. However, the overlap between the datasets is small, suggesting many false positives with low functional relevance. Therefore, we integrated ~800 sequence features and protein characteristics such as cellular function and protein-protein interactions in a machine learning approach to score likely functional SUMOylation events (iSUMO).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
